A Guide to the Nan Overton West Papers, ca. 1959-2001
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Papers, ca. 1959-2001
Library of Virginia
37849, 38300
9.45 cubic feet and 1 microfilm reel
Nan Overton West
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These collections were given to the Library of Virginia by Nan Overton West in 2000 and 2001.
Biographical/Historical Information
Nan Overton West is a life-long resident of Lubbock, Texas. She attended Lubbock Public Schools, Texas Technological College, Randolph-Macon Woman's College, and The University of Texas, where she graduated with a B.A. degree in 1941. After retiring from the family businesses, she published a genealogical history of her husband Pete's family, The Wests and The Rays and Their Allies: Southern Families from the Colonies to Texas. In 1991 this book was awarded First Place for Family History and Grand Prize for Writing by The Texas State Genealogical Society. In 1992 she published He Wore a Pink Carnation, a biography of Dr. Marvin C. Overton, her father and a pioneer physician in West Texas. She also has written The Overtons: 700 Years with allied families from England to Virginia, Kentucky, and Texas (1997) which will be followed by another genealogical history about the Jennings families and twenty related lines.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, ca. 1959-2001, consisting of the genealogical research files on the Overton, West and Ray families and their allied families compiled by Nan Overton West. Folders principally consist of research files concerning specific individuals and families and correspondence exchanged with individuals concerning specific families. The research files contain genealogical notes concerning family lines abstracted and/or copied from census records, military records, Bible records, patriotic organization applications, family group sheets, pedigree charts, extracts from published sources, newspaper clippings, family descendants' newsletters, photographs, genealogical charts, and court records, including deed books, order books, will books, and marriage records. Correspondence concerning family lines also appears in this collection and often includes research files along with their letters. This material remains within the respective correspondents file. Miscellaneous correspondence concerning a certain family is filed by the family's surname and arranged chronologically.
These research files were the principal resource material Nan West used to write The Wests and The Rays and Their Allies: Southern Families from the Colonies to Texas and The Overtons: 700 Years with allied families from England to Virginia, Kentucky, and Texas. The files generally remain in the order kept by Nan West.
Research files exist for the following Overton allied family surnames: Bickley, Booker, Bosley, Briscoe, Brockman, Burch, Burkham, Clough, Compton, Crook, Garland, Garnett, Gerard, Goldsmith, Grundy, Harratt, Harris, Jennings, Lawson, Leake, McCarty, Muscoe, Poindexter, Shipp, Slye, Snow, Swan, Taylor, Terrell, Waters, and Whitworth. West allied family surnames are Ashley, Berry, Boatner, Culver, Dashley, Egner, Martin, Norris, Sanford, Smith, Swain, Ward, Weideman, Weyman, and Wyatt. Ray allied family surnames include Caldwell, Culpepper, Dean, Gillespie, Grant, Harrison, King, Kirk, Peek, Richards, Tatum, Wyatt, and Young.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Within each series, files are arranged alphabetically.
Organization
The collection is organized into the following series:
I: Overton Family
II: Overton Allied Families
III: West Family
IV: West Allied Families
V: Ray Family
VI: Ray Allied Families
Contents List
- Overton Family (Box 1-7)
  - Leslie Ann Alden, correspondence, 1993, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Overton family research files (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Michelle T. Amsbury, correspondence, 1993, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lois Baird, correspondence, 1987-1988, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Census records (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Colonial Dames research files (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Contemporary authors of Robert Overton research files (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondents list (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - English Overton family research files (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Excerpts from Robert Overton's manuscript (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Family group charts (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Family group sheets (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alice Figures, correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Rhoda T. Fone, correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Elizabeth Green, correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "He Wore a Pink Carnation: a Biography of M. C. Overton," by Nan West (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Kathleen Hunt, correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Arthur Jones, correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - M. B. Jones, correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Jo Kirk, correspondence, 1990, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Long Island Overton family research files (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bill Loyd research files (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Jack Mayer, correspondence, 1987-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meade County, Kentucky, marriage bonds concerning the Overton family (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Norma J. Mittendorf, correspondence, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - David Norbrook, correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Orphan Brigade research files (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Overton family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1973, 1987-1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Overton family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Overton family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Overton family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Overton family, miscellaneous e-mail correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Overton family, miscellaneous e-mail correspondence, 1997-2001 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Overton family timetable (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Overton Only," volume 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Overton Only," volume 1B (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Overton Only," volume 1C (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Overton Only," volume 1D (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Overton Only," volumes 2A and 2B (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Overton Only," index for volumes 1A-1D (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ella Overton research files (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Garland Terrell Overton research files (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - George Overton research files (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - George Buck Overton research files (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - James Overton research files (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Jo and Todd Overton, correspondence, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - John Overton research files (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Lady Claire Overton, correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Marvin C. Overton III, correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Marvin C. Overton III, correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
  - Marvin C. Overton III, correspondence, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Marvin C. Overton III, correspondence, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Marvin C. Overton III, correspondence, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Marvin C. Overton III, correspondence, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Marvin C. Overton research files (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Nannie J. Overton, correspondence, 1967, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Robert Overton research files (also see microfilm in this box) (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Tennessee Overton family research files (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Texas Overton family research files (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Waller Overton, correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Gospell Observations and Religious Manifestations," by Robert Overton (microfilm) (Box 5)
  - William Overton research files (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Pedigree charts of Dorothy L. Overton (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - David H. Peterson, correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Photographs (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Publications excerpts (Box 6, Folder 5-10)
  - Research notebook containing notes on Meade and Hardin County, Kentucky, records (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Temple M. Simmons, correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Nevel Overton Slack, correspondence, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Nevel Overton Slack, correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Paul Urbahns, correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Historical Society, correspondence, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Public Libraries, correspondence, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Virginia State Library, correspondence, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Ruth Warner, correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Ruth Warner, correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Jack Whitmeyer, correspondence, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Susan M. Williams, correspondence, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Wills (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Overton Allied Families (Box 8-15)
  - Karen L. Austin, correspondence, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Don L. Booker, correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Don L. Booker, correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Booker-Leake-Clough families research files (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bosley family research files (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Brockman family research files (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Brooks family research files (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Carr family research files (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Clough family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Clough family research files (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondents list (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Alliene Ellis, correspondence, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "The Family and Ancestry of William Dabney of Virginia and His Two Wives," by William L. Deyo (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Farrar family research files (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Claude Faulkner, correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Claude Faulkner, correspondence, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Claude Faulkner, correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Gardiner family research files (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Garland family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Garland family research files (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Garland-Wilson families research files (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Garnett family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1972, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Garnett family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Garnett family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Garnett family, miscellaneous e-mail correspondence, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Garnett family research files (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Unrelated Garnett family research files (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "Richard Brooke Garnett," manuscript by Truett Tyler (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Gerard family, royal lineage from Claude Faulkner (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
  - Gerard-Slye-Briscoe families research files (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
  - Glover family research files (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Grundy family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1969-1973, 1989-1995 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Grundy family research files (Box 10, Folder 8-10)
  - Jimmy Grundy, correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Harratt family research files (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Harris family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1989-1994 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Harris family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Harris-Slye families, miscellaneous correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Joan Talbot Helbig, correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Catherine M. Whitworth Hilbert, correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Jewell family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Eve L. Kinney, correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Lawson family research files (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - John Crook Lawson and Arethusa Grundy, miscellaneous correspondence, 1969-1994 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - John Crook Lawson and Arethusa Grundy research files (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Leake family research files (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Jeanie Luckhoo, correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - McCarty family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - McCarty family research files (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - McCarty-Crook families, miscellaneous correspondence, 1988-1994 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - McCarty-Crook families research files (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Massie family research files (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Muscoe family research files (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Overton allies, miscellaneous correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Overton allies, miscellaneous correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Overton-Howerton families research files (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Jane Pearce, correspondence, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Jane Pearce, correspondence, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Jane Pearce and Truett Tyler, correspondence, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Pocahontas research files (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Poindexter Descendants' Association, directory, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Poindexter Descendants' Association, newsletters, 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Poindexter Descendants' Association, newsletters, 1992-1994 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Poindexter Descendants' Association, newsletters, 1994-1996 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Poindexter family genealogical notes, compiled by John B. Poindexter, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Poindexter family genealogical notes, compiled by John Poindexter Landers (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Poindexter family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1989-1996 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Poindexter family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Poindexter family research files (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Robertson family research files (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Vivian Rudisill, correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Peggy Rush, correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - George E. Russell, correspondence, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - St. Peter's Parish (New Kent County), register and vestry book abstracts (Poindexter family) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Shipp family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Shipp family research files (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Taylor family research files (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Terrell-Bickley families research files (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Truett Tyler, correspondence, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Waters family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Whitworth family genealogical notes, compiled by Harold Whitworth, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Whitworth family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Whitworth Family Association, correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Whitworth family research files (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - W. W. Woods, correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Wooldridge family research files (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Bill Wyatt, correspondence, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- West Family (Box 16-17)
  - Jim Allen, correspondence, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - T. N. Boschert, correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Family tree questionnaires (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Genealogical and pedigree charts (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Linda Maltby, correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Adell Morgan, correspondence, 1969-1987 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Joe West, correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Joe West, correspondence, 1987-1991 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Joe West, correspondence, 1992-1998 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - West family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1985-1991 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - West family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - West family research files (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
  - West family research files gathered since book published (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - West-Ray book readers, correspondence, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- West Allied Families (Box 18-20)
  - Ashley-Lashley-Lesley families research files (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Zula Atwood, correspondence, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Berry family research files (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Boatner family, miscellaneous correspondence and research files, 1970-1991 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
  - Culver family, miscellaneous correspondence and research files, 1970-1994 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Joseph A. Culver research files (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Egner-Eigner families, miscellaneous correspondence and research files, 1990-1994 (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
  - Kenny Goode, correspondence, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Martin family research files (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Norris family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Norris family research files (Box 19, Folder 3-6)
  - "The Norris Family of Maryland," by Thomas M. Myers (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Sanford family research files (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Smith family, miscellaneous correspondence and research files, 1991-1993 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - South Carolina West family research files (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Swain family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1970-1999 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Swain family research files (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
  - Swain-Norris families, miscellaneous correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Ward family research files (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Whitmire family research files (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Wyatt family research files (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Ray Family (Box 21-22)
  - Census records (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - John Massey, correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Ray family, confederate records (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Ray family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1963-1972, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Ray family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Ray family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1992-1998 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Ray family members, correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Ray family newsletters, 1987-1988 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Ray family newsletters, 1989-1990 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Ray family newsletters, 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Ray family research files (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - Ray family research files gathered since book published (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - George Ray research files (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - John Benjamin Ray research files (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Major W. Ray research files (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Mollie Ray, correspondence, 1969-1974 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Unrelated Ray family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - W. L. and Ruby Lee Ray research files (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Marlene Scott, correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Ellaree Dean Speer, correspondence, 1970-1972, 1986-1991 (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Ray Allied Families (Box 23-27)
  - "An Account of the Short Life and Death of Reverend John Lee," by Jesse Lee (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Arnett-Haynes family research files (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Caldwell family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1969-1994 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Caldwell family research files (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Culpepper family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1967-1970, 1989-1995 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Culpepper family research files (Box 23, Folder 6-7)
  - Unrelated Culpepper family research files (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Dean family, miscellaneous correspondence (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Dean family research files (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - "The Dean Family: the Descendants of Drury Dean," by Mary Emily Smith Witt (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - "Descendants of John Wesley Dean," by Lewis Griffin, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Alliene Ellis, correspondence, 1987-1993 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Gillespie family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Gillespie family research files (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Grant family research files (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Lewis Griffin, correspondence, 1978-1992 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Roberta Griffin, correspondence, 1969-1991 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Harrison family research files (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - "The King's Ley," by Gladys Howard Thompson (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Lee family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1969-1972, 1985-1990 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Lee family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Lee family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Lee family, miscellaneous correspondence, 1993-2000 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Lee family research files (Box 25, Folder 3-4)
  - Lee family research files from Eva Boyce (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Lee family research files from Roberta Griffin (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Lee family research files from Wilma McMillan (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Lee family research files from Dora Ray (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Lee family research files gathered since book published (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Burwell Lee research files (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Burwell and Hugh Lee research files (Box 25, Folder 11-12)
  - G. W. Lee research files (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Hugh Lee research files (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Hugh Lee research files from Cora Lee Anderson (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Joe Dean Lee, correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Joe Dean Lee, correspondence, 1991-1998 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Colonel Richard Lee research files (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Unrelated Lee family research files (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - William Young Lee research files (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Wyatt Lee research files (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Lovella Lee McCubbin research files (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Mailing list, correspondence, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Mailing list of book recipients (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Peek family research files (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Ray allied families research files from Alliene Ellis (Box 27, Folder 2-5)
  - Richards family research files (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Ellaree Dean Speer, correspondence, 1970-1990 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Ellaree Dean Speer, notebook on Culpepper family (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Ellaree Dean Speer, notebook on Dean family (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Tatum family research files (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Texas Lee family research files (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Wyatt family research files (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Young family research files (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Overton-West-Ray genealogical and pedigree charts (oversize folder)